

Amitrakshar Sanyal

Nationality: Indian (+91) 07044258067

Date of birth: 04/05/2001

Gender: Male

■ Email address: sanyalamitrakshar@gmail.com

Website: https://linktr.ee/amitrakshar

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/amitrakshar-sanyal-a59376191/

▼ Twitter: https://twitter.com/AmitraksharS **GitHub:**: https://github.com/amitrakshar01

🗣 Address: Bally Durgapur Samabaya Palli Prantik Near Debangan Lodge, 711205

Howrah (India)

ABOUT ME

A Machine Learning Engineer with excellent statistical knowledge and the ability to identify fine points of data in a sea of information. Being well-versed with the concepts of Data Structures and Algorithms gives me the ability to write efficient codes in programming languages like Python, Java, C, C++, JavaScript. Able to process new data quickly and communicate effectively with anybody. Having experience with working in an Agile environment makes me not only an engineer with coding experience but also a customer-centric person making products for people.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern

Mungr [08/11/2021 - 15/12/2021]

City: Mumbai Country: India

Building a Dashboard from scratch using HTML, CSS, Javascript where teachers getting hired in Ed-Tech companies can test their ability and compare with other teachers globally.

Mentor

Script Winter of Code 2.0 [02/11/2021 – Current]

City: Remote Country: India

Open Source Mentor for more than 200 students.

Mentoring with the following 2 projects:

- 1. Blood Buddy: It is a website developed for easy blood donation during COVID-19. The website's concept is that once a person registers, he will be able to view his nearest blood banks & can contact them, and also those who need blood will be able to speak with one another through the website.(https://github.com/2024-SANDHYA/ Blood-Buddy)
- 2. Thief Detection: This project helps to detect that whether a person coming to your house is a thief or not, while you are away from your house enjoying your holiday or a trip by sending an alert message and also an attached image of the person in your email address.(https://github.com/neha07kumari/Thief Detection)

Machine Learning Contributor

GirlScript Winter of Contributing [01/10/2021 - 10/12/2021]

City: Remote

- 1. Contributed to Open Source Machine Learning repositories.
- 2. Worked with Maximum Likelihood Estimation problem.
- 3. Documented lots of code.

Technical Team Member

realme [01/01/2021 - 04/05/2021]

City: Remote Country: India

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Technology

Institute of Radio Physics and Electronics, University of Calcutta [06/02/2019 - Current]

Address: (India) www.caluniv.ac.in

TECHNICAL STACK

Programming Languages

Python, R, C, C++, JavaScript, HTML(Markup Language), CSS(Style Sheets), Java

Machine Learning Tools

Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Tensorflow, Pytorch, etc.

Database

MySQL, MongoDB

IDEs

Jupyter, Google Colab, IBM Watson Studio, Spyder, VSCode, Codeblocks, Intellij, PopSQL

PROJECTS

Machine Learning based Fake News Detection(Natural Language Processing)

 $[\ 01/01/2022 - 01/01/2022\]$

Pulled out a dataset from kaggle.com and used it to detect the legibility of the news. The model I used was Logistic Regression, got accuracy about 91%.

https://github.com/amitrakshar01/fake_news_detection

Euphoria- Stream music anywhere

[10/12/2021 - 12/12/2021]

A static but fully responsive music web app made entirely with pure HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. The web app is made entirely with pure logic and no frameworks used.

https://github.com/amitrakshar01/Euphoria

IOT BASED TEMPERATURE AND HUMIDITY MONITORING SYSTEM FOR HILL STATIONS

[04/05/2021 - 04/06/2021]

Built a Temperature and Humidity Monitoring System using NodeMCU. Wrote a Conference paper on IEEE where a model was built form the same and used specifically for tea estates and other plantations in the hill stations for accurate monitoring of essential parameters.

Portfolio Optimization

[09/09/2021 - 12/09/2021]

Using classical algorithms, specifically Efficient Frontier Method to find out an overall optimized portfolio.

https://github.com/amitrakshar01/Portfolio-Optimization

Mungr Dashboard

[01/11/2021 - 15/12/2021]

A dashboard made for teachers to get hired by Ed-tech companies. The features:

- 1. Teachers can give a test to evaluate their readiness for an Ed-Tech company.
- 2. The dashboard will check the technical specifications of their device because Ed-techs need to know that.
- 3. The teacher will have a virtual staffroom to showcase their skills.
- 4. The Ed-techs will have a separate login for hiring them.

This is part of my Internship Project at an early-stage startup called Mungr(mungr.org). The Software team is led by me.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Bengali

Other language(s):

English Hindi

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2 LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2 SPOKEN PRODUCTION C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Cycling

Record of 54kms on single cycling ride 4hrs)

Professional Photographer

Writer with one publication(Native language: Bengali)